#### William Davis

| Los Angeles, California | P: 323.595.5317 | williamd123@juno.com

#### Technical Skills:

Ability to plan and install LAN and WAN technology; Experience and working knowledge of Cisco IOS; Worked with HP, Dell, Barracuda Networks, Juniper, and IBM network solutions; Project planning skills for network deployment and upgrades; Performed IPv4 to IPv6 integration; Network configuration and troubleshooting skills for TCP/IP, STP, QOS, PPP, Frame-Relay, Site-to-Site and Remote VPN, NAT, RIP, EIGRP, OSPF, IS-IS, MPLS, and BGP protocols; Wireless 802.11x, Cisco ASA 5500, 5520, 5580 series, & VoIP planning, configuration, and installation; Network provisioning and bandwidth optimization skills; VLSM/CIDR planning, design and configuration skills.

## **Professional Experience:**

Los Angeles, CA Network Engineer Consultant (07/99-09/2002; 04/2003 - Present)

- Troubleshot a broad range of network and administrative solutions
- Implemented and upgraded client networks and devices
- Designed and developed enterprise networks and security solutions
- Created backup and design strategies to meet performance levels
- Configured and updated Cisco 1800, 2600, 3600, 5500, 6500 & 7500 series routers
- Configured and updated Cisco 2900, 3000, 4000 Catalyst, 7000 series Nexus, & 8000 switches
- Applied knowledge of routing protocol such as RIP, EIGRP, OSPF, IS-IS, and BGP
- Wireless 802.11a-n WPA/WPA2 installation, configuration and troubleshooting
- Working knowledge of TCP/IP, PPP, Frame-Relay, MPLS, LACP, VLANs, VTP, STP, RSTP+
- Modified and managed automation scripts using Pearl and PHP scripting.
- Clients include: Outsource Technical, Collier International, Kaiser Permanente, etc...

# CCH, INC., Torrance, CA 90503

(09/2002 - 4/2003)

## Technical Support Representative

- Performed installation and operation of ProSystem fx tax software
- Supported Microsoft Windows '2000, XP, Novell Netware, Lotus Notes, and Citrix
- Provided support for network connection issues
- Performed quality control testing of software products
- Created call tracking tickets via Heat SOS software

# SMART & FINAL CORPORATION, Commerce, CA 90040

(12/1998 - 07/1999)

### Office Automation Analyst

- Controlled email accounts via Microsoft Exchange and Outlook 97/98
- Maintained projects plans in Microsoft Project 98 and Microsoft Visio software
- Produced reports in ad-hoc query tools such as SAS, SAP, and COGNOS
- Created technical documentation to support the user community
- Trained and lead technical staff on MS Mail 3.0 to Exchange Server 5.5 e-mail migration



# SMART & FINAL CORPORATION, Commerce, CA 90040 Computer Operator

(12/1990 - 12/1998)

- Controlled the IBM 390 and ES9000 MVS/ESA mainframe utilizing JES2 IMS
- Analyzed terminal problems through TSO and VTAM
- Monitored and controlled DB/2 and VSAM databases
- Analyzed program disk space requirements and JCL abends
- Optimized Oracle 7.3/8.0, Sybase 10/11, and MS SQL 6.5/7.0 RDBMS
- Controlled IBM AIX 4.3 RS/6000 computer systems
- Performed Dell & IBM Server Administration

#### **EDUCATION:**

West Los Angeles College, Culver City, CA

• Cisco Networking Administrator

Professional Career Institute, Cerritos, CA

CompTIA A+ Certified Professional

Professional Career Institute, Cerritos, CA

Microsoft Certified Professional

DeVry University, Pomona/LA, CA

Computer Information Systems

Urban League Training Center, LA, CA

Certified Computer Operator

Grant High School, Van Nuys, CA

Social Studies

